Finding Aid for St. Margaret’s Episcopal Church (Hazel Park, Mich.) records, 1927-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. Margaret’s Episcopal Church (Hazel Park, Mich.) records 1927-2007
St. Margaret’s Episcopal Church (Hazel Park, Mich.)
2 linear feet and 2 oversized volumes
2008074 Ba 2
St. Margaret’s Episcopal Church of Hazel Park, Michigan, member of the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan, operated from 1927 to 2007; registers of baptisms, burials, confirmations, marriages; and vestry minutes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Donated by the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan (donor no. 1059 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Episcopal Mission of St. Margaret's, Hazel Park, was started in the Odd Fellows Temple in 1927. Services moved to Goulson Ave. near John R. St. in 1929. A new building was built on Stephenson Highway between Annabell and Moorhouse and dedicated on Christmas Eve, 1948. An updated facility would be built at this site in 1965. St. Margaret's was admitted as an incorporated parish of the Episcopal Diocese of Michigan on February 3, 1959 and ceased its ministry on November 18, 2007.
The records of the church include both registers of births, baptisms, burials, and names of communicants, as well as registers of church services and minutes of the vestry.
Subjects:
Episcopal Church--Michigan--Hazel Park.; Hazel Park (Mich.)--History.; Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Hazel Park.; St. Margaret's Episcopal Church (Hazel Park, Mich.)
- Registers
  The Registers series (0.5 linear feet and 2 oversize volumes) contains a complete record of baptisms, burials, confirmations, and marriages during the eighty year mission of the church.
  - Baptisms, 1927-1955, Confirmations, 1927-1955, Marriages, 1930-1955, Burials, 1928-1955 (Volume 1)
    (Oversize vol. no. 1)
  - Baptisms, 1956-1969, Confirmations, 1956-1966, Marriages, 1956-1974, Burials, 1956-1982 (Volume 2)
    (Oversize vol. no. 2)
  - Baptisms, 1969-2005 (Box 1)
  - Burials, 1982-2007 (Box 1)
  - Confirmations, 1951-2007 (Box 1)
  - Marriages, 1974-2004 (Box 1)
- Organizational
  The Organizational series (1.5 linear feet) contains registers of church services, which record attendance, as well as minutes of the vestry.
  - Building Plans Committee, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Property Title (Box 1)
  - Register of Church Services
    - 1929-2007, 6 volumes (Box 1)
  - Vestry Minutes
    - 1959-1962 (Box 1)
      (incl. Articles of Incorporation)
    - 1963-2001, 11 volumes (Box 2)
    - 2002-2005 (Box 2)
      (incl. 2002 Statistical Report)
    - 2006-2007 (Box 2)
      (incl. Final Communications and Property Distribution)